Meet Stuart, Kevin & Bob.
Minions is a family, animation, adventure film directed by Kyle Balda.
Minions Stuart, Kevin and Bob are recruited by Scarlet Overkill, a super-villain who,
alongside her inventor husband Herb, hatches a plot to take over the world.
Scarlet Overkill (voice), played by Sandra Bullock.
Herb Overkill (voice), played by Jon Hamm.
Walter Nelson (voice), played by Michael Keaton.
Madge Nelson (voice), played by Allison Janney.
Professor Flux / Tower Guard (voice), played by Steve Coogan.
Reine Elizabeth II (voice), played by Jennifer Saunders.
Minions is a 2015 American animated comedy film directed by Pierre
Coffin and Kyle Balda and written by Brian Lynch.
Produced by Illumination Entertainment, it is a prequel to Despicable Me
(2010) and the third installment in the Despicable Me franchise.
The film features the voices of Coffin (as the Minions), Sandra Bullock, Jon Hamm, Michael Keaton,
Allison Janney, Steve Coogan and Jennifer Saunders, with Geoffrey Rush as the narrator.
In the film, the Minions search for their replaceable evil boss after, one-by-one,
accidentally killing all their past leaders throughout history.
Minions premiered in London on June 11, 2015, and was released in
the United States on July 10, by Universal Pictures.
It received mixed reviews from critics.
The film grossed $1.16 billion, becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2015, the
second-highest-grossing animated film and the tenth-highest-grossing film of all time.
A sequel, Minions: The Rise of Gru, was released in 2022,
while a third film is due to be released in 2026.
The film explores themes of assistant, villain, prequel,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.